The mother of all movies.
Hot Shots! is a action, comedy, war film directed by Jim Abrahams.
The gang that created Airplane!
and The Naked Gun sets its sights on Top Gun in this spoof.
Topper Harley is a talented but unstable fighter pilot with
an axe to grind: clearing the family name.
His mission is to avenge his father and save a mission
sabotaged by greedy weapons manufacturers.
He also gets involved in a relationship with Ramada Thompson,
a woman with an unusually talented stomach.
makes fun of a variety of other films, from Dances
with Wolves to The Fabulous Baker Boys.
Topper Harley / Rhett Butler / Superman, played by Charlie Sheen.
Kent Gregory, played by Cary Elwes.
Ramada Thompson / Scarlett O'Hara / Lois Lane, played by Valeria Golino.
Admiral Benson, played by Lloyd Bridges.
Lt. Commander Block, played by Kevin Dunn.
Jim 'Wash Out' Pfaffenbach, played by Jon Cryer.
is a 1991 American parody film directed by Jim Abrahams, co-writer and
co-director of Airplane!, and written by Abrahams and Pat Proft.
It stars Charlie Sheen, Cary Elwes, Valeria Golino, Lloyd Bridges, Jon Cryer,
Kevin Dunn, Kristy Swanson, Bill Irwin, and Efrem Zimbalist Jr.
The film is primarily a spoof of Top Gun, with some scenes spoofing other popular films, including 9½ Weeks, The
Fabulous Baker Boys, Dances with Wolves, Marathon Man, Rocky, Superman, First Blood, and Gone with the Wind.
A sequel, Hot Shots!
Part Deux, was released in 1993, with Sheen, Golino,
Bridges and Jerry Haleva reprising their roles.
The film explores themes of secret mission, bad luck,
parody, drill instructor, jet crash.
The tone is lighthearted.